(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-23T13:58:28.623282",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
幽閉 利口 逝く 前 に
Before you go off being smart in solitary confinement...
ユーレイじゃ利口になりたり
Wishing to be smart as a ghost...
幽閉ストップ 知ってないし
You don't even know about stopping solitary confinement,
勘弁にしといてなんてざんねん
and asking for mercy is such a shame.
人様願う 欠片のアイロニー
The irony in the fragments people wish for—
誰もが願う 無機質なような
everyone wishes for something inorganic,
一歩先に 始めてたいような
wanting to start one step ahead,
先が見えない ヴァージンハッピーショー
in a blind virgin happy show.
無いの一新にお願いいっこ
Give me one brand-new wish,
愛も変わらずおまけにワーニング ワーニング
love unchanged, plus warning, warning!
無いのはあなたにお願いいっこ
Give me one wish for you,
貼り詰めた思い込みを
tightly clinging to preconceptions.
レフトサイド ライトサイド
Left side, right side,
牙を剥き出して パッパッパ
baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa!
照れくさいね
how embarrassing.
レフトサイド ライトサイド
Left side, right side,
牙を突き出して パッパッパッ ハハ
let your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa, haha!
you are king
無邪気に遊ぶ 期待 期待のダーリン
Playing innocently, you're the darling I expected.
健気に笑う 痛い 痛いの消える
When you laugh admirably, all my pain disappears.
無様に〇ねる 苦い 想いもなくなって
Clumsily dying, bitter feelings fade away too.
ラララ ブウ ラッタッタ
La-la-la, boo, rat-ta-ta!
嫌い 嫌いの最低 泣いてダウン
I hate it, hate it, the worst—crying and down.
毎回新しく お願いいっこ
Just like always, here's a brand-new wish:
愛も変わらずピックアップのワーニング ワーニング
love unchanged, picking up warning, warning!
無いのはあなたにお願いいっこ
Give me one wish for you,
貼り詰めた思い込みを
tightly clinging to preconceptions.
レフトサイド ライトサイド
Left side, right side,
牙を剥き出して パッパッパ
baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa!
邪魔臭いね
how bothersome.
レフトサイド ライトサイド
Left side, right side,
牙を突き出して パッパッパッ ハハ
let your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa, haha!
you are king
毎回新しく お願いいっこ
Just like always, here's a brand-new wish:
愛も変わらずピックアップのワーニング ワーニング
love unchanged, picking up warning, warning!
無いのはあなたにお願いいっこ
Give me one wish for you,
貼り詰めた思い込みを
tightly clinging to preconceptions.
レフトサイド ライトサイド
Left side, right side,
牙を剥き出して パッパッパ
baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa!
邪魔臭いね
how bothersome.
レフトサイド ライトサイド
Left side, right side,
牙を突き出して パッパッパッ ハハ
let your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa, haha!
you are king
毎回新しく お願いいっこ
Just like always, here's a brand-new wish:
愛も変わらずピックアップのワーニング ワーニング
love unchanged, picking up warning, warning!
無いのはあなたにお願いいっこ
Give me one wish for you,
貼り詰めた思い込みを
tightly clinging to preconceptions.
レフトサイド ライトサイド
Left side, right side,
牙を剥き出して パッパッパ
baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa!
邪魔臭いね
how bothersome.
レフトサイド ライトサイド
Left side, right side,
牙を突き出して
let your fangs poke out...
Halo, halo, halo, halo, halo, halo!
Hello, hello, hello, hello, hello!
Hai, wow...
Hi, wow...
You are KING, right?
Hai, semuanya! Hai, halo, everybody! Hai!
Hi, everyone! Hi, hello, everybody! Hi!
I'm... Yes, I'm Squirrel from the Magical Forest! Hai!
I'm... Yes, I'm Squirrel from the Magical Forest! Hi!
Tahu rula, tahu rula, sudah berapi-api, oke?
It's gonna start, we're getting all fired up, okay?
We we just started and Mori, Mori, ngeting dulu. Kanah? Hahaha!
We just started and... Mori, Mori, getting ready first. Right? Hahaha!
Oke, so, first song is KING, and well...
Okay, so, first song is KING, and well,
because I'm the closing, so I chose KING as the first opening song! Yes!
And also, if you like my performance, yes, don't forget, don't forget
there's hashtag above here, or you know, don't forget, don't forget to post the screenshot, to post your... what is it again? To post your Ayunda...
Risu Experience! Yes, with hashtag #AyundaRisu3D and make it trending!
And also don't forget, don't forget, don't forget to share this to your whole family, to your friends, to your colleagues, and yes.
How how is it? How is it? KING? KING? Oh, wait. Hahaha!
Yes, you can see me, aku kiyowo! Kiyowo! Itta, ahaha!
Yes, you can see me, I'm so cute! Cute! Ow, ahaha!
Akiyowo! Hahaha! Hello, I'm finally 3D, guys! Yes,
So cute! Hahaha! Hello, I'm finally 3D, guys! Yes,
the the memer squirrel is finally in 3D! Amazing!
But, but this is only the beginning, right? Because there will be more, because this is only the beginning. So, eto ne...
But, but this is only the beginning, right? Because there will be more, because this is only the beginning. So, um...
Look at me, look at me all you want before we actually moving, all right?
So after this we're going to check my bedroom. Yes, I think you've seen it previously, just a glimpse of it, right?
So, jadi habis ini tuh, Risu mau ngecek kamar ya, oke? Oke?
So, after this, Risu is gonna check her room, okay? Okay?
Yes, are you ready? Oh my god, kiyowo! Oh, fluffy tail, metayii! Asewasewasewasewasewase! Metayii, oleyoleyoleyoleyoleyoley!
Yes, are you ready? Oh my god, so cute! Oh, fluffy tail, so pretty! So cute! So pretty!
So, you know what? Let's move on to a more comfortable place, to my bedroom, okay? Let's go!
Buru-buru! Gampa! Risuuu!
Hurry, hurry! Do your best! Risuuu!
窓を開けて 小さく呟いた
I opened the window and whispered softly,
誰もいない 部屋で一人
All alone in an empty room.
朝が来たよ 土砂降りの朝が
Morning has come, a pouring morning.
私のネジを 誰か巻いて
Won't someone wind my screw up?
昔のアニメにそんなのいたっけな
Was there someone like that in old anime?
羨ましいな 皆に愛されて
I'm so envious, loved by everyone.
馬鹿な事言ってないで支度をしなくちゃな
Stop saying stupid things and get ready.
涙の跡を隠す為
To hide the traces of my tears,
もう口癖になった「まぁいいか」
"Oh well" has become my catchphrase.
昨日の言葉がふと頭を過る
Yesterday's words suddenly cross my mind:
「もう君には全然期待してないから」
"I don't expect anything from you anymore."
そりゃまあ私だって自分に期待なんてしてないけれど
Well, I suppose I don't expect much from myself either, but...
アレは一体どういうつもりですか
What on earth was that supposed to mean?
喉元まで出かかった言葉
Words that were right at the tip of my tongue,
口をついて出たのは嘘
What came out of my mouth were lies.
こうして今日も私は貴重な言葉を浪費して生きていく
And so today too, I go on wasting precious words.
何故隠してしまうのですか
Why do I always hide things away?
笑われるのが怖いのですか
Is it because I'm afraid of being laughed at?
誰にも会いたくないのですか
Don't I want to meet anyone at all?
それ本当ですか
Is that really true?
曖昧という名の海に溺れ息も出来ないほど苦しいの
Drowning in a sea called ambiguity, it hurts so much I can barely breathe.
少し声が聞きたくなりました
I wanted to hear your voice just a little.
本当に弱いな
I really am so weak.
一向に進まない支度の途中 爛々とした頭で思う
In the middle of getting ready, my head throbbing, I think:
「もう理由を付けて休んでしまおうかな」
"Maybe I should just make up an excuse and stay home."
いやいや分かってますって なんとなく言ってみただけだよ
No, no, I know that, I was just saying it for no reason.
分かってるから怒らないでよ
I know, so don't get mad at me.
幸せだろうと 不幸せだろうと
Whether happy or unhappy,
平等に 残酷に 朝日は昇る
The sun rises equally and cruelly.
生きていくだけで精一杯の私にこれ以上何を望むというの
To me, who is barely scraping by just living, what more could you ask for?
何故気にしてしまうのですか
Why do I care so much?
本当は愛されたいのですか
Do I really want to be loved?
その手を離したのは誰ですか
Who was it that let go of that hand?
気付いてますか
Have you realized yet?
人生にタイムカードがあるなら終わりの時間は何時なんだろう
If life has a time card, I wonder what time it clocks out.
私が生きて分の給料は誰が払うんですか
Who pays the salary for the life I've lived?
ありがとうって言いたいよ
I want to say "thank you."
一度だけでも良いから 心の底から大泣きしながら
If only once, from the bottom of my heart, crying loudly...
ありがとうって言いたいよ
I want to say "thank you."
なぜ隠してしまうのですか
Why do I hide things away?
本当は聞いて欲しいのですか
Do I really want you to listen?
絶対に笑ったりしないから
I promise I won't ever laugh.
話してみませんか
Won't you talk to me?
口を開ければ分からない
Once I open my mouth, I don't know.
思っているだけでは伝わらない
Just thinking it won't convey anything.
なんてめんどくさい昨日でしょう 人間というのは
What a troublesome yesterday it is to be human.
ありがとうって言いたいよ
I want to say "thank you."
ありがとう 一度だけでもいいから 心の底から女泣きしながら
Thank you, if only once, crying from the bottom of my heart.
ありがとうって言いたいよ
I want to say "thank you."
なぜ隠してしまうのですか
Why do I hide things away?
本当は聞いて欲しいのですか
Do I really want you to listen?
絶対に笑ったりしないから
I promise I won't ever laugh.
話してみませんか
Won't you talk to me?
口を開かなければ分からない
If I don't open my mouth, you won't know.
思っているだけでは伝わらない
Just thinking it won't convey anything.
なんてめんどくさい昨日でしょう 人間というのは
What a troublesome yesterday it is to be human.
Iya guys ya, ada... ada satu di mana orang-orang tuh masih kaget gitu
Right guys, there's... there's one where people are still surprised like that.
Waktu hardgalin Risu nyanyi Hello How Are You pas debut dan masih di-share sampai sekarang.
Back when Risu sang "Hello How Are You" during her debut and people are still sharing it until now.
So, people were actually just discovered uh recently, just discovered my... uh what is it?
So, people actually just discovered... uh recently, just discovered my... uh, what is it?
m... debut video where Risu actually showed up singing Hello How Are You.
uh... debut video where Risu actually showed up singing "Hello How Are You".
So, for me, for me personally though, it's... it's such a life-changing experience.
Yeah. Wah, I I started to to sound old right now, yeah.
Yeah. Wow, I... I started to... sound old right now, yeah.
It's just It's just that without that without that first experience, I wouldn't be here right now and you wouldn't know Ayunda or even Risu.
And why I choose that song, it's because it has like... uh, what is it again?
And why I chose that song, it's because it has like... uh, what was it again?
um personal attachment in it.
um, personal attachment to it.
So, the OG, the OG would know, right? Yes, right?
So the OGs, the OGs would know, right? Yes, right?
So, uh when I was singing the song, I I I really...
was it it again? I really tried to hold my myself to not become so teary-teary.
what was it again? I really tried to hold myself... to not become so teary-teary.
And also, I would like to introduce you my room. This is where I actually spend my most of my time 24/7. There is almost That's all.
And also, I would like to introduce you to my room. This is where I actually spend most of my time, 24/7. There's almost... That's all.
my water bottle that always uh been my friend.
my water bottle that's always... been my friend.
Yes. The the mustache, finally you've seen it. And also above there, there is uh framed Alice and U uh picture, yes.
Yes, the mustache! Finally you've seen it. And also above there, there is a framed Alice and U picture, yes.
Also if you like my... uh my desktop, you can share it. You can share it with #AyundaRisu3D, right?
And also, while singing, I... uh I have... show you my bed.
And also, while singing, I... uh I have... showed you my bed.
I can actually sit on the bed. Mmm, we can actually do something nice on bed right now.
I can actually sit on the bed. Mmm, we can actually do something nice on the bed right now.
Ahahaha. Bed, beto. Goodね.
Ahahaha. Bed, beto. Good, right?
Just... just enough shenanigans, right? I will... I will... I will let you... uh request some things from me, okay?
Just... just enough shenanigans, right? I will... I will... I will let you... request some things from me, okay?
Request... uh what is it? Pose pose. Oh yeah, right. Pose now.
See, you can... you can see it. You can see the tail from every angle, okay? Look at them hips. Oh my god!
See? You can... you can see it. You can see the tail from every angle, okay? Look at those hips! Oh my god!
All right. I will... oh my goodness! Oh my goodness gracious! Oh lord!
See, uh okay, you know what, the... the 3D show is for my tail only, all right?
And you... you want me to pose? Kawaii, kawaii pose?
Ah so so so so. Ah, ale, ale, ale, nelfon. Nelfon, guys. Ale, ale. Siapa ya? Siapa ya?
Ah so so so so. Ah, ringing, ringing, ringing, phone. Phone, guys. Ale, ale. Who is it? Who is it?
Ane? Dari loro? Ee? Ane? Halloween?
Ane? From loro? Eh? Ane? Halloween?
Hai! Halo! Halo! Oh my god!
Hi! Hello! Hello! Oh my god!
Halo! Halo! Wah, ada spoiler! Siapa ya?
Hello! Hello! Wow, there's a spoiler! Who is it?
Aku? Aduh! Bisa dilihat? Aduh. Aku dilihat... Risu senpai. Aduh, aku malu. Aduh, jangan jadi malu. Aduh, aku malu, aduh. Aku...
Me? Ouch! Can you see me? Ouch. I'm being seen... Risu senpai. Ouch, I'm embarrassed. Ouch, don't be embarrassed. Ouch, I'm embarrassed, ouch. I...
Aduh... Uh, Kaila, Reine dan Anya.
Ouch... Uh, Kaila, Reine, and Anya.
Woa, woa, woa, woa! Wah, kacau sih, sudah daftar.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa! Wow, this is messed up, already signed up.
Jadi, halo! Halo! Bagaimana? Apa mengambil saya?
So, hello! Hello! How is it? Did you pick me?
Kucubet! Kucubet... Ekornya, pipinya pengen kucubet. Aduh!
Kucubet! Kucubet... Her tail, her cheeks, I want to pinch them. Ouch!
Berarti kita bagi tiga aja nih. Wah, jangan sampai guntut.
So we just divide it into three. Wow, don't let it get cut.
Untung menghindari pencurian terhadap buntut, bagaimana kalau kita bermain game saja ya, teman-teman? Mohon maaf ya. Waduh! Waduh, alih kan? Game alihan.
To avoid theft of the tail, how about we just play a game, friends? Sorry ya. Oh boy! Oh boy, shifting? Shifting game.
Boleh, boleh, apa-apa? Untung mengalihkan isu, jadi kita akan main gesture game ya.
Sure, sure, what is it? To distract from the issue, so we'll play a gesture game, yeah.
Oke. Pasti pasti sudah lumayan mengertilah gesture game ya. Jadi Risu yang pose, nanti kalian yang tebak gitu. Eh terus ada kayak time limitnya gitulah. Pokoknya asalkan kalian tau, bilang aja gitu.
Okay. Surely you already understand the gesture game, right? So Risu poses, then you guys guess it. Eh then there's like a time limit. Basically as long as you know, just say it.
Oke? Oke, siap. Oke deh. Apakah kalian sudah siap? Oke. Let's go! Round pertama, game start! Woo!
Okay? Okay, ready. Okay then. Are you guys ready? Okay. Let's go! Round one, game start! Woo!
Ayo, jangan.
Come on, don't.
Mulai, mulai, mulai.
Start, start, start.
Nyiram bunga?
Watering flowers?
Balapan, balapan?
Racing, racing?
Nyuter, nyuter, nyuter...
Turning, turning, turning...
Naik odong-odong?
Riding a kiddie ride?
Naik... apa?
Riding... what?
Naik bajai?
Riding a bajaj?
Nyuter motor?
Riding a motorcycle?
Di luar negeri?
Abroad?
Nyuter, nyuter, nyuter...
Turning, turning, turning...
Supir, supir, supir, supir!
Driver, driver, driver, driver!
Ada baterainya?
Does it have a battery?
Supir truk! Supir truk!
Truck driver! Truck driver!
Waaah! Benar! Waaah!
Waaah! That's right! Waaah!
Jadi, jadi begitu, teman-teman, cara mainnya.
So that's how you play, guys.
Oke?
Okay?
Udah, udah ngerti?
You guys get it?
Oke, oke.
Okay, okay.
Sudah, sudah.
Got it, got it.
Next... Hmm, Risu sekarang memikirkan apa ya?
Next... Hmm, what is Risu thinking of now?
Kalian mau... mau next, next?
You guys want next, next?
Next, next, next, next... Let's go!
Next, snigers? Waduh, oke.
Next, sneakers? Whoa, okay.
Round 2! Game start!
Itu kayaknya larinya itu...
It looks like its running is...
Eh, eh, eh, larinya itu...
Hey, hey, hey, its running is...
Iya, kan? Larinya itu... aduh, larinya itu...
Right? Its running is... oh, its running is...
Iya kan? Apa tuh? Apakah boleh disemprot?
Right? What is it? Can it be sprayed?
Yang netral, yang netral. Yang netral.
The neutral one. The neutral one.
Ninja dulu, ya ninja!
Ninja first, yeah ninja!
Waktu itu apa tadi? Rain, ya? Ninja!
What was it earlier? Rain, right? Ninja!
Ninja!
Yang netral. Yang netral sekali ya.
The neutral one. Extremely neutral.
Wah, harusnya Risu bikin yang susah-susah... Ah, jangan dong. Jangan dong.
Man, Risu should've made it harder. Ah, no, don't.
Jangan dong!
Don't do that!
Masih pengin enggak melihat Risu gerak? Masih ada satu lagi... Mau enggak lanjut? Lanjut, gas, gas, gas.
Still want to see Risu move? There's still one more... Want to continue? Gas, gas, gas.
Ronde ketiga.
Round three.
Round 3! Game start!
Hmm... Menggambar apa?
Hmm... Drawing what?
Dia, dia... mengapapal, merapal mantra itu.
He, he... chanting, chanting a spell.
Eh, pelayangan, wuih!
Uh, flying, whoa!
Itu... menyihir orang?
That... enchanting people?
Iya, dia kayak menyihir orang. Iya, benar... mengusir? Sedikit lagi!
Yeah, like enchanting people. Right, expelling? Just a little bit more!
Wizard? Eh, sorceress!
Yang penyihir! Uh, penyihir.
The sorcerer! Uh, sorcerer.
Penyihir kamu. Jadi, 3D, wah!
You're a sorcerer. So, 3D, wow!
Ayo dong, mau dong! Amin, minta Yago ya.
Come on, I want some! Amen, ask Yago.
Aku mau sih gepeng ya.
I want to be flat, huh.
Kalau begitu, teman-teman, terima kasih sudah mau bermain bersama Risu dan melihat penampilan Risu yang ini...
In that case, guys, thank you for playing with Risu and seeing her performance like this...
...untuk touch, wuih, keren banget! Beat-nya itu loh, rhythm-nya itu loh!
...for the touch, whoa, so cool! The beat, the rhythm!
Kalau begitu... mohon maaf, teman-teman, saya usir kalian keluar!
In that case, I'm sorry, guys, I'm kicking you out!
Sampai jumpa, senpai!
See you, senpai!
Oke, senpai, terima kasih banyak senpai, ini senpai, goodbye!
Okay, senpai, thank you very much senpai, here's senpai, goodbye!
Wah, keren, keren, keren, keren. Wah!
Wow, cool, cool, cool, cool. Wow!
Wah, bersemangat, guys! Walaupun begini-begini masih bersemangat ya, teman-teman.
Man, energetic, guys! Even like this, still energetic, guys.
Tadi udah kan, ninja run, kalian sudah lihat, you've seen I've fulfilled my promise to do ninja run, okay?
Earlier we did ninja run, you've seen I've fulfilled my promise to do ninja run, okay?
So because I've have moved a lot already, I think I haven't get dinner, so I'm actually kind of hungry, all right?
So because I've moved a lot already, I think I haven't got dinner, so I'm actually kind of hungry, all right?
So I'm trying to find some nuts, all right? Ah.
Aduh, kacang nih, aduh lapar banget nih, aduh.
Man, nuts, man, I'm so hungry, man.
Huli! Ada kacang, guys! Ini adalah kesempatan emas, teman-teman, apabila kalian ingin memberikan Risu kacang, tentu saja dengan superchat kalian bisa memberikan kacang yang banyak sekarang juga.
Huli! There are nuts, guys! This is a golden opportunity if you want to give Risu nuts, with superchat you can give lots of nuts right now!
Jangan lupa hasilkan dari Risu 3D dan berikan kacang lebih banyak biar Risu bisa makan, bentar.
Don't forget Risu 3D and give more nuts so Risu can eat, wait.
Lebih banyak dong, woi! Masih sedikit doang, eh.
Give more, hey! Still just a little, eh.
Entar harus tunggu ya. Satu, dua, tiga, give me more nuts.
Have to wait. One, two, three, give me more nuts.
Alright, give me more nuts, please. Thank you. I will eat your nuts, okay, this is from you.
This, this, not yours, right?
This... This is not yours, right?
I'm going to eat it.
I'm gonna eat it.
How, how do you feel having your nuts being eaten by me, all right?
I will, I will start eating.
A bowl of your nuts.
All right, all right, all right, all right. I've eaten your nuts, all right?
But, I've seen, I've seen something suspicious right there.
All right, I'm, I'm, I'm going to take it for, for a while now.
All right, I'm... I'm gonna take it for... for a while now.
Jadi tuh...
Jadi karena sekarang tuh, kebetulan lagi streaming 3D ya.
Kayaknya tuh...
Kayaknya tuh seru gitu kalau Risu itu...
Apa sih? Isi celengannya gitu.
Satu...
Dua...
Tiga...
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Where's the money? Open up!
Risunya lagi nggak ada.
Risu!
Muka Eeq!
Eh, ada yang makan di sebelah aku. Sabar, sabar! Risu buka dulu bentar!
Buka!
Gimana, sih?
Ada. Oke, kan bilang juga di kamar aku nggak ada.
Ternyata ada di sini!
Eh, kamu sih aku kan jadi dilabrak sama Moona, tahu nggak?
Iya, soalnya...
Soalnya kemarin tahu nggak?
Siapa tahu kamu ngambil celengannya?
Kemarin pas bawa...
Iya ada berapa? Iya ada berapa? Tadi baru tiga doang sih tapi masih banyak.
Jangan bilang-bilang.
Nanti lagi boke.
Mau ambil nggak? Mau ambil nggak? Mau ambil nggak?
Aku nggak tahu apa-apa!
Maaf-maaf. Nanti-nanti Risu, oke.
Kan-kan tadi percaya aja. Risu akan beli yang lebih bagus, oke?
Yang baru, iya yang lebih bagus, yang lebih gede, iya yang lebih gede.
Benar!
Betul!
Sama-sama makanan ya. Oke, siap! Siap, Risu aman, guys, aman-aman.
Nah, kalau aman, aduh, harus disogok dulu.
Enggak apa-apalah, happy.
Sering-sering aja kalau gitu ya.
Oke, nanti Risunya...
Enggak apa-apa.
Kebetulan yang akan kan udah senang nih, udah senang ya.
Oke, jadi kebetulan kita bertiga, bagaimana kalau kita menyanyikan Mars kita bertiga?
Boleh?
Oke, kalau gitu.
Ayo nyanyi bareng! Hi15!
ganbari ~ risu !
Ganbari~ Risu!
moon moon moona dayo !
Moon moon Moona dayo!
io foria ! o bisa !
Io foria! O bisa!
la - la - la , la - la - la , area15
Lala-la, lala-la, Area15
la - la - la , la - la - la , bersama selalu
Lala-la, lala-la, bersama selalu
la - la - la , la - la - la , area15
Lala-la, lala-la, Area15
la - la - la , la - la - la , let 's join us !
Lala-la, lala-la, let's join us!
tiap aku jahil in kamu , percayalah itu tanda suka padamu
Tiap aku jahilin kamu, percayalah itu tanda suka padamu
kau kira ku tak menyadari ?
Kau kira ku tak menyadari?
tentu saja ku tahu tapi ku ikuti maumu
kita - kita semua selamanya bersama kian hari semakin sayang
Kita-kita semua selamanya bersama kian hari semakin sayang
saat air mata jatuh sekejap lagi kau genggam tanganku , saling memandang
Saat air mata jatuh sekejap lagi kau genggam tanganku, saling memandang
hei semua ! sudah siapkah ? ayo berangkat !
Hei semua! Sudah siapkah? Ayo berangkat!
ayo semangat ! yuk , bisa , yuk !
Ayo semangat! Yuk, bisa, yuk!
let 's go , friends ! , kita bersama merajut kisah yang happy - happy ! kumpulkan semua impian dan keberanian
Let's go, friends! Kita bersama merajut kisah yang happy-happy! Kumpulkan semua impian dan keberanian
ayo maju selangkah ! jangan sampai menyerah !
Ayo maju selangkah! Jangan sampai menyerah!
walaupun jalannya masih jauh dan gelap suatu hari pasti perasaan ini ' kan ku sampaikan kepadamu
Walaupun jalannya masih jauh dan gelap suatu hari pasti perasaan ini 'kan ku sampaikan kepadamu
wait for it !
Wait for it!
Ganbari~ Risu!
Do your best, Risu!
Moon moon Moona dayo!
It's Moon Moon Moona!
Io foria! O bisa!
Iofi's here! You can do it!
La-la-la, la-la-la, Area 15
La-la-la, la-la-la, bersama selalu
La-la-la, la-la-la, always together,
La-la-la, la-la-la, Area 15
La-la-la, la-la-la, let's join us!
Tiap aku jailin kamu, percayalah itu tanda suka padamu
Whenever I tease you, believe me, it's a sign I like you.
Kau kira ku tak menyadari? Tentu saja ku tahu, tapi ku ikuti maumu
You think I wouldn't notice? Of course I knew, but I played along with your wishes.
Yoppii! Sekali lagi, sebab terjadi itu tidak
Yoppii! Once more, because that shouldn't happen,
Disimpan sendiri, menari di wonderland kita-kita semua paling asyik di dunia ini
Kept to ourselves, dancing in wonderland, we're the coolest in this world!
Saat kesedihan datang melanda hati, lewat layar itu
When sadness comes to strike the heart, through that screen,
Bagi senyuman, selisih waktu tidak masalah seluruh dunia bisa mendengar!
Share a smile, time differences don't matter, the whole world can hear!
Saat kesedihan datang melanda hati
When sadness comes to strike the heart,
Lewat layar itu, bagi senyuman
Through that screen, share a smile,
Selisih waktu tidak masalah, yuk, ceki dot!
Time difference doesn't matter, yeah, check it out!
Akhirnya setelah 17 tahun menunggu!
Finally, after 17 years of waiting!
Hu-uh! Hula!
Whoo! Hula!
Awalnya... kala hari panas, kala hari dingin
At first... when the day is hot, when the day is cold,
Ayolah kita lebih sering bicara
Let's talk more often,
Kusayang, kusayang, kusayang! You love me? I love you!
I love you, I love you, I love you! You love me? I love you!
Barengan semua ayo mulai, tu-wa-ga-pat, let's laugh a lot!
Together everyone let's start, one, two, three, four, let's laugh a lot!
Ayo mulai, twogather, let's laugh a lot!
Let's start... let's laugh a lot!
Apabila suatu hari mimpi-mimpiku akan terkabul
If one day my dreams come true,
Semoga kita semua lebih banyak lagi menangis dan tertawa
May all of us cry and laugh even more,
Bersama selamanya!
Together forever!
Akhirnya mulai terlihat hari-hari cerah yang kita impikan, inilah saatnya 'tuk...
Finally, the bright days we dreamed of start to show, now is the time to...
...kusampaikan kepadamu perasaanku!
...convey my feelings to you!
Kala hari panas, kala hari dingin, ayo lagi...
When the day is hot, when the day is cold, let's...
Kita lebih sering bicara, saat hari cerah, saat hari hujan, ayo lebih sering bermain!
Talk more often, when the day is sunny, when it rains, let's play more often!
La-la-la, la-la-la, Area 15
La-la-la, la-la-la, bersama selalu
La-la-la, la-la-la, always together,
La-la-la, la-la-la, Area 15
La-la-la, la-la-la, let's join us!
Akhirnya kita berjoget ria parguy!
Finally, we danced happily, parguy!
Gimana? Gimana tadi? Gimana?
How was it? How was it just now? How?
Untuk sekalian teman-teman, terima kasih! Wah, ini kita bertiga...
To all of you friends, thank you! Wow, the three of us...
Kalau begitu, bagaimana menurut kalian kamar Risu? Kamar Risu kawaii? Surprisingly, it's so clean!
If so, what do you guys think of Risu's room? Risu's room is kawaii? Surprisingly, it's so clean!
Kok celengan Moona nggak ada?
Why is Moona's piggy bank missing?
Risu yang ngumpetin, ya? (Bukan aku, kok!)
Risu hid it, right? (It's not me!)
Kok Moona curiga sih sama aku? Jahat banget! (Pasti si Risu nih yang ngumpetin!)
Why are you suspicious of me, Moona? So mean! (It must be Risu who hid it!)
Eh, nggak baik loh nuduh orang! (Jangan berantem, dong!)
Hey, it's not good to accuse people! (Don't fight!)
Celengannya ada di sini, kok! Makasih ya, udah datang.
The piggy bank is right here! Thanks for coming.
Jangan lupa ya, guys! Ya?
Don't forget, guys! Right?
Dadah!
Bye-bye!
Wah, on-cam seram banget, guys. Nah, kalau begitu tuan-tuan, teman-teman...
Wow, being on-cam is really scary, guys. Well then, ladies and gentlemen, friends...
Karena sudah ada Yofis sama Moona, saatnya kita touch the grass. Jadi kayak kita're going outside. We're gonna touch the grass for a while...
Since Yofi and Moona are here, it's time for us to touch the grass. So like, we're going outside. We're gonna touch the grass for a while...
Wah, I'm here now! Yes, we're outside!
Wow, I'm here now! Yes, we're outside!
We're outside, yes! Akhirnya, guys, kita keluar. Jadi tuh ada tujuannya kenapa Risu mau keluar.
We're outside, yes! Finally, guys, we went out. So there's a reason why Risu wanted to go out.
Jadi tuh mau ngeliatin ya, kira-kira tuh hutan ajaib Risu tuh seperti apa. Ini tuh kira-kira penampilannya ya mirip-mirip kayak ginilah, gitu.
So I want to show you what Risu's magical forest is like. This is roughly what it looks like, something like this.
So my... my magical forest looks kind of like this. I just want to show you the... the beautiful scenery. Yes, anu, waktu...
So my... my magical forest looks kind of like this. I just want to show you the... the beautiful scenery. Yes, um, my...
Na, magical forest-nya itu, eh, tuh, indah nan, tapi, anu, seram juga, loh.
Well, that magical forest, um, is beautiful, but, um, it's also quite scary, you know.
Kok ada, kok bisa ada di sini? Ada Risosaurus kah?
Why is there... how could it be here? Is there a Risosaurus?
Risosaurus! Aku Risosaurus, lho.
Risosaurus! I am a Risosaurus, you know.
Eh, bener? Aku Risosaurus. Lucu, tapi aneh. Kenapa? Hari ini...
Eh, really? I'm a Risosaurus. Cute, but weird. Why? Today...
どうしたの？リスちゃんが3Dだって聞いたから、今日は来たの。
What's wrong? I heard Risu's going 3D, so I came today.
ええ、来たんだ！あれ！
Huh, you came! Wait—
リトサウルスありがとうだけど、これはリトサウルスじゃないな、じゃないみたいな。
Thanks for the Ritosaurus, but this isn't quite a Ritosaurus... doesn't look like one.
リトサウルスだよ。
It is a Ritosaurus.
あれ、いや、この声はね、この声はね、もしかして、もしかして、オガさんですかね？え？オガさんだよね？え？
Wait, no, this voice... could this voice possibly be... Oga-san? Eh? It's Oga-san, right? Eh?
やっぱりオガさんだよね！
I knew it was Oga-san!
やっぱりオガさんだよね！なんとかだね！おらあ！
No matter what! Raaah!
どうも、こんばんは。
Good evening.
あらリスちゃん、3Dおめでとうございます。あ、ありがとうございます。ホールスターズ3期生、荒咬オガが、え、ゲストで参戦です。
My, Risu-chan, congratulations on your 3D. Ah, thank you. Holostars 3rd Gen, Aragami Oga, participating as a guest.
リスちゃんどう、あ、ほら、リスちゃんこれ、ほら、え、だ、だ、誰、新しい、新しい、あの、私の、あの、リトサウルス、あ、届いてくれる？
Risu-chan, how... Ah, look, Risu-chan, look at this. Who, who is this new, new... my, um, Ritosaurus, ah, could you bring it over?
いや、新しいリトサウルスだよ、ほら、みてん。
Yeah, it's a new Ritosaurus. Look, check it out.
あ、リトサウルス、あ、同じ、同じだよ。
Ah, Ritosaurus, ah, the same, it's the same!
同じリトサウルスが、そうそうそうね、え、かわいい。
The same Ritosaurus, right, right. Ah, cute.
かわいいえ、これ何すんのじゃあ、リトサウルス揃ったら。
Cute. Eh, what are we gonna do now that we have matching Ritosauruses?
あ、これね、リトサウルスはね、あの、オガさんからのプレゼント。そうそうそうそう、かわいいでしょよねーん。
Ah, this, Risu-chan, is a present from Oga-san. That's right, isn't it cute?
うん、とってもかわいい。ええ。
Yeah, very cute. Yeah.
あ、そしてね、あの、この2人が揃ったらね、あれをお討ちかしなよね？あれ、あれを歌うのか？はい、そうそうそう、あれ、あの、はらぱん、パンパンパン！
Ah, and also, when these two are together, we gotta defeat *that*, right? Wait, we're gonna sing that? Yes, that's right, that... hara-pan, pan pan pan!
harapan pan panpan
ほら 手と手 繋いで
Look, holding hands,
まだ 知らない 毎日 へ
To an unfamiliar everyday.
harapan pan panpan
めくるめく この 世界 で
In this swirling world,
叶え ましょう harapan pan
Let's make our wishes come true, harapan pan!
harapan pan panpan
ほら 手と手 合わせて
Look, putting our hands together,
奏で ましょう pan panpan pan
Let's play music, pan panpan pan!
harapan pan panpan
めくるめく 毎日 で
In our swirling everyday,
また 生まれる harapan pan
Another harapan pan is born!
harapan adalah hal yang ada di hati semua orang
Harapan is something that exists in everyone's heart,
小さな harapan も 大 ～ きな harapan も
Small harapan and huge harapan,
神様 から 皆 に 等しく 分け与え ら れ た hara pan
The hara-pan evenly bestowed upon everyone by God.
夢 の よう な harapan も 時 に は 怖 ～ い hara pan も
Harapan like a dream, and sometimes scary hara-pan too.
例えば 私 の harapan は 、 サ ・ テ ・ ソルト ・
For instance, my harapan is... sa, te, salt...
お歌 、 いたずら 、 どんぐり 、 ナッツ 、
Songs, mischief, acorns, nuts,
おか … ！？ ころね … ！？ おかころーー！！！！
Oka...!? Korone...!? Ogakorooo!!!!
そして 俺 の hara pan は 、 うめぇもの 全般 、 かっこいいもの 全般 、
And my hara-pan is all kinds of delicious food, all kinds of cool things,
イラスト に ゲーム ！ ゲーム ゲーム ゲーム ！！！
Illustrations and games! Games, games, games!
ささやかな 願い事
A modest wish,
積み木 積み重ねて ！
Stacking building blocks high!
世界 を まるごと 染め上げ ちまえ
Let's dye the whole world in our colors!
私 の harapan ・ 俺 の harapan
My harapan, my hara-pan,
2 つ 合わせ て ハラハラ パンプン
Combining two together, hara-hara pan-pun,
願い を 叶え て みせ まし ょ う
Let's make our wishes come true.
ざっくり まとめて ハラ パンパン
Summed up roughly: hara pan-pan.
二人 の harapan 共に harapan
Two people's harapan, together with harapan,
harapan pan panpan
ほら 手と手 叩いて
Look, putting our hands together,
鳴らし ましょう pan panpan pan
Let's play music, pan panpan pan!
harapan pan panpan
めくるめく 毎日 で
In our swirling everyday,
また 生まれる harapan pan
Another harapan pan is born!
ねえねえ 見て見て 綺麗な お星 はらぱん！
Hey hey, look look! A beautiful giant star harapan!
ははっ 本当だね！
Haha, that's right!
そうだ 、 あの流れ harapan に 3 回 harapan pan panpan をしたら 、
That's right, if you do harapan pan panpan three times to that shooting harapan,
harapan が叶うそうだよ？
your harapan will come true?
本当？じゃあどんな harapan にしようかな～
Really? Then what kind of harapan should I make~?
この先どんな困難があっても、
No matter what hardships lie ahead,
二人がいつまでも幸せの harapan を持てますように…
May the two of us always hold the harapan of happiness...
ころねころねころねころね おかころねころね…
Korone Korone Korone Korone, Okayu Korone...
おかころころねころね おかゆころねころねころね…
Okayu Korone Korone, Okayu Korone Korone...
ada harapan yang cerah dan ada harapan yang mendung
There are bright harapan and cloudy harapan,
神様から 皆に 等しく分け与えられた hara pan panpan
The hara-pan-panpan evenly bestowed upon everyone by God,
あなたも あなただけの 特別の harapan を持って
You too, holding your own special harapan,
この 目眩く 世界に 鮮やかな 色取りを ！
Bring vivid colors to this dazzling world!
本当に大事なのは
What's truly important
たった一つだけ
is just one thing
明日のことはわからないけど
We don't know about tomorrow, but
私の harapan ・ 俺の harapan
My harapan, my hara-pan,
力合わせて ハラハラ パンプン
Joining our forces together, hara-hara pan-pun,
何でもできる気がするんだ
I feel like I can do anything.
二人の harapan 共に harapan
Two people's harapan, together with harapan,
ここからはじまる ハラ パンパン
Starting from here, hara pan-pan.
カリスマ的 塞翁が馬
A charismatic blessing in disguise,
私の harapan ・ 俺の harapan
My harapan, my hara-pan,
人生まるごと ハラハラ パンプン
Our whole life, hara-hara pan-pun.
君の幸せ また願って
Wishing for your happiness once more,
二人の harapan 永久に harapan
Two people's harapan, forever harapan,
これからもよろしくね
Here's to the future as well.
harapan pan panpan
ほら 手と手 繋いで
Look, holding hands,
笑い ましょう pan panpan pan
Let's smile, pan panpan pan!
harapan pan panpan
めくるめく 毎日 で
In our swirling everyday,
また 生まれる harapan pan
Another harapan pan is born!
harapan pan panpan pan ！
harapan pan panpan pan !
ほら、ぱん、ぱん、ぱんすね。
That's right, pan pan.
ほらぱんすっごかったよね。
Pan pan was amazing, right?
楽しかったね。
It was fun, right?
楽しかった。いやいやいやいや。
It was fun. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
あのね、あの、私の3D配信に来てくれてありがとう！
Um, you know, thank you for coming to my 3D stream!
すごく楽しかった。
It was a lot of fun.
ね。にゃんにゃん、あの
Right? Meow meow, um...
今から、あの、本当にありがとうございましたね、本当に。
And now, um, thank you so much, really.
いや、でもね、やっとね、3D慣れて、みんなね、こうやってお披露目もできて、
Well, but, you know, getting used to 3D at last,
being able to unveil it to everyone like this,
本当に良かったなと思います。
I really think it's great.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
じゃあ、オガさんと、今日はね、楽しかった。あとね、3分ぐらい喋れって言われた今。
Well, Oga-san, today was fun, you know.
They told me to talk for about 3 more minutes.
また遊ぼ、あのこれあげる。いやこれ、まだね、もうちょっと喋れるんだって、どうする？
Let's play again, um, I'll give you this.
Wait, they said we can talk a bit more!
えー、あのね、もらっちゃったけど。
Eh, um, you know, I got one.
ポーズ、ポーズ！ポーズ取る？ポーズ取る？
Pose, pose! Shall we strike a pose?
はあ～、すごい！
Phew... Amazing!
どうする？どんなポーズ取る？作ろうよ。よーし、すごい！
What should we do? What kind of pose?
Let's make one. Alright, amazing!
かわいいよね。ねえ、私の可愛いよ。
It's cute, right? Hey, mine is cute.
あ、そうかね、リスちゃんも可愛いね。エリスね、ほら。
Oh, that's right, Risu is cute too.
Risu's, see.
ほらお尻こんな感じ。
Look, the butt is like this.
あれ、私の、お尻... あららら
Huh, my butt... Oh my, oh my.
リスちゃんもね、尻尾ね、ふわふわでいいよね。
Risu, your tail is fluffy
and nice too, right?
ねえ。
Yeah.
あ、オガさん尻尾欲しい？尻尾ね、尻尾欲しいか、作るかな、これ。
Ah, Oga-san, do you want a tail?
A tail, huh? Shall I make one?
作らないかな？あれ、だめだな。
Won't you make one? Huh, guess not.
可愛いんだよ。可愛いよ、これ。
It's cute, you know. It's cute, this.
あ、可愛い？だめだな、リスハウス嫌がってない、これ？嫌がってない、これ？大丈夫？
Ah, cute? No way, Risu's house,
aren't they hating this? Are you okay?
なんじゃよ！ いやあ
What the heck! (laughter) Yeah...
はい、あ、そうかね、リスちゃんちっちゃいね。
Yes, ah, that's right,
Risu is small, right?
うんうんうん。ねえ、オガさんちっちゃいね。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hey, Oga-san is small.
はい、いや、オガさんは本当に高いんですけど。
Yes, well, Oga-san is really tall, though.
うん、まあね。ほら、オガスタいちでかいからな。
Yeah, well, you know.
Because Oga-st is the biggest.
あ、そうね。どれぐらい高いんですか？
Ah, is that so? How tall are you?
えっとね、192cmから200mまで大きくなります。
Let's see, I grow from 192 cm
to 200 meters.
あれ、怖いじゃん。怖いよ！ビルよりでかくなれるから。
Huh, that's scary. Scary!
Because I can get bigger than buildings.
あれいわ、オーガビル。オーガビル！
Oh my, Oga Building. Oga Building!
いや、すごいね。すごい？ありがとね。
Man, that's amazing. Amazing? Thanks.
いや、でもなんか不思議な感じするの、リスちゃんとこうやって3Dで並んでると。
Yeah, but you know, it feels kind of strange
standing here in 3D with Risu like this.
お、あのね、えっと、3Dもらったら、あのなんか、あれ、あのムービー、ムービー作ってる？
Oh, um, you know, once you get 3D,
like, are you making movies?
ムービー、ムービー作る？おお、いいぞ。
Making movies? Oh, nice.
あの、ワールドドミネーションムービー？
Um, World Domination Movie?
そうそうそうそうそう。YES！おお、いいね。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. YES! Oh, nice.
是非とも一緒に撮ろう。
By all means, let's shoot it together.
なんか、オーガは、えっと、なんだろう、あ、まあ、マジの中、うん。なんだろう、あ、でかいものってなんだろう、なんの名前？
Something like, Oga, um, I wonder,
what is a big thing called? What's the name?
なんだろう。巨人？
I wonder. Titan?
巨人？ああ、マジの巨人ね。巨人になって、そしてあの街になんか、ぶわー！
Titan? Ah, real titan. Become a titan,
and in the town, like, WHOOSH!
あ、マジでぶわーってね。
Ah, seriously, whoosh, right?
ぶわーって出すんだね。
You output whoosh, right?
はいはいはい。
Yes, yes, yes.
わかりました。じゃあね、一緒に今度ムービー撮りましょう。
Understood. Well then,
let's shoot a movie together next time.
あ、そうね。あ、これ可愛い。これ可愛い。
Ah, this is cute. This is cute.
私、あのなんか1回プラッシュ欲しいね。
Me, um, like,
I want a plush once.
あ、本当？でもね、それなんかね、もう家帰りたいって言ってるから。
Oh really? But you know, it's saying
it wants to go home already.
あ、そっか。あ、これ、これあげる。あ、ありがとう。
Ah, I see. Ah, here, I'll give you this.
- Ah, thanks.
じゃあ、こちらの2つはね、あの、見てる皆さんにプレゼントするかもしれません。
Well then, these two might be presented
to everyone watching.
はい！てなわけでね、今日楽しかった。ありがとね。みんなもありがとね！
Yes! And with that, today was fun.
Thanks. Thanks everyone too!
えい！じゃあこれからも頑張って！またね！バイバイ！
Hey! Well then, do your best
going forward! See you! Bye-bye!
That was that was that was really crazy.
That was, that was,
that was really crazy.
That was like, oh, what is it again?
That was like,
oh, what is it again?
That was really fun. It's
I can't really imagine that it's actually happening right now.
I can't really imagine
that it's actually happening right now.
すごいね、はらぱんぱんぱんぱん。
Amazing, right?
Harapan pan pan pan pan.
Uh and then, and then, uh we're we're going to look at the scenery a little bit more, I'm sorry because there was there was an evil being before.
Uh, and then, and then, uh, we're going to look
at the scenery a little bit more. I'm sorry...
There's a lot of flowers and the the look is pretty aesthetic.
There's a lot of flowers
and the look is pretty aesthetic.
And yeah, there's a lot of pretty flowers. Cute, isn't it?
And yeah, there's a lot of pretty flowers.
Cute, isn't it?
Daphne, ficus, iris, maackia, lythrum, myrica, sabia, flos.
Daphne, ficus, iris, maackia,
lythrum, myrica, sabia, flos.
響く 僕の 願いよ 未来よ
Resound, my wish, my future,
絶え間無い 後悔よ
endless regrets,
体感八度五分の夢は 綻び散ってしまった
the sensational dream
has fallen apart.
daphne, ficus, iris, myrica
daphne, ficus
iris, maackia
lythrum, myrica, sabia
thymus
ribes
abelia
sedum, felicia
ochna, lychnis
拝啓 僕の願いよ
To whom it may concern, my wish...
未来よ 絶え間無い後悔よ
my future, endless regret...
体感八度五分の夢は 綻び散ってしまった
The sensational dream of 8 degrees and 5 minutes fell apart.
daphne, ficus
iris, maackia
lythrum, myrica, sabia
thymus, ribes
abelia, sedum
felicia, ochna, lychnis
再啓 君の想いは 憂いは 回る感情論は
Re-disclosed: Your thoughts, your sorrows, swirling sentimental arguments...
半径八十五分の世界に囚われたまま
trapped in a world with a radius of 85 minutes.
本音を挿し 綻びた今日を 溢れた一切に
Inserting real intentions into cracked today, overflowing into everything,
薪を焼けて 風に乗せて 錆びた空を彩る
burning firewood and putting it in the wind to color the rusted sky.
燻んだ日々に 丁寧に 飾った花は 直ぐに 枯れていく
The flowers carefully decorated on smoked days quickly wither away.
愚鈍な 僕は 夢 から 覚めて
Stupidly, I woke up from a dream
綴った意味も ない ない ない ない
that had no meaning at all...
君が僕にくれた 声も 色も 揺るぎない愛情も
The voice and color you gave me, and your unwavering love,
二人きりの空に光った 星も 疾風に散ってしまった
and the stars shining in our two-person sky scattered in the gale.
難局の末のモノクロの疲弊に 季節は色褪せて
Seasons fade to color in the monochrome exhaustion after difficulties,
熱を帯びて澱む 擦れた街に零れる
growing feverish and murky, spilling over into the rubbed city.
燻んだ日々に 丁寧に
On smoked days, carefully...
辿った先には 花が咲く筈 利口な君は 夢を見た筈
Flowers should bloom at the end of the path; clever you must have dreamed.
悟った素振りで水をした 木漏れ日の中に 柔らく咲いた花は
With a knowing gesture pouring water, flowers blooming softly in sunbeams
雲の上で違う星で 夢の先で揺れてる
are swaying beyond dreams on a different star above the clouds.
燻んだ日々に 丁寧に 飾った花は 直ぐに 枯れていく
The flowers carefully decorated on smoked days quickly wither away.
愚鈍な僕は 夢から覚めて 綴った意味も ない ない ない
Stupid me, waking from a dream, meaning nothing at all...
不毛な日々に 丁寧に 綴った紙に 花を描いた
On barren days, carefully drawing a flower on paper,
不遇な僕らは 夢に負けて 誓った筈もなかったことにした
Our unfortunate selves lost to dreams and pretended we never swore.
daphne, ficus, iris, maackia, lythrum, myrica, sabia
thymus, ribes, abelia, sedum, felicia, ochna, lychnis
daphne, ficus, iris, maackia, lythrum, myrica, sabia, thymus, ribes, abelia, sedum, felicia, ochna, lychnis, flos
Oh, flos, flos ne... Ayunda...
Oh, flos... flos, right? Ayunda...
There's a lot of Ayunda in flos, huh?
Ayunda, can you say hi? Ha-hi!
Ayunda, can you say hi? Hi-hi!
Is... Ayunda came to, you know...
Flos is my like I've explained to you before, really back...
Flos is my—like I've explained to you before, really back...
Flos was my comfort song,
and there's a lot of Ayunda in there because the original cover of my flos is full of Risu, right?
So I'm giving you more Ayunda. Do you want to see Ayunda in action?
Oh wait, oh wait, my mic...
Yes, I want to show you my mic. This is the mic that I personally designed since my debut.
So this is the nut mic! I sing on your nuts!
Yay, yay, yay, yay! Yes, yes, yes, yes!
That's, that's the, uh, emojis! Yes!
You use that, thank you!
Also, once again, use hashtag #AyundaRisu3D.
Don't be, uh, so bewitched by my performance, okay?
Wah, trending natta yo! Wah, sugoi!
Wow, it's trending! Wow, amazing!
Jadi trending, guys! Ayunda gaming!
It's trending, guys! Ayunda gaming!
Wah, masa gamernya keluar, gila gila gila!
Man, the gamer side came out, crazy crazy!
Thank you, share more #AyundaRisu3D hashtag, alright?
Also, do you want to see Ayunda in action? 3D Ayunda in action once in a lifetime, alright?
Hai, domo! Ayunda desu wa!
Hi there! It's Ayunda!
Hai, hai, halo everybody! I am Ayunda. Thank you so much for watching us, Ayunda and Risu... until now we can finally get 3D! Wow, 3D is so great!
Hi, hi, hello everybody! I am Ayunda. Thank you so much for watching us, Ayunda and Risu... until now we can finally get 3D! Wow, 3D is so great!
And also, while being Ayunda, I would like to, what is it? I would like to tell you a little bit of, uh, announcement.
Yes, what is the announcement, Risu? So, the announcement is, yes, uh later there will be a mini live, yes, collab of Gen 1 Hololive Indonesia, right? So here's the announcement, chuchu!
Yes, what is the announcement, Risu? So, the announcement is, yes, uh later there will be a mini live, yes, collab of Hololive Indonesia 1st Generation, right? So here's the announcement, tada!
Wow, I look very safe. So, sugoi ne!
Wow, I look very safe. So amazing!
That's, that may be Ayunda, right? Right, Ayunda? Yes, I think that's me.
Ne? Wah, safe so ne! Sugoi ne! Mature, you look so mature. I mean, I look so mature. Thank you, Ayunda.
Right? Wow, so safe! Amazing! Mature, you look so mature. I mean, I look so mature. Thank you, Ayunda.
You're welcome. Yes, also the live, mini 3D live will be on 23 September, same time 8 PM, yes, don't miss it, alright? Okay!
You're welcome. Yes, also the live, mini 3D live will be on September 23rd, same time 8 PM, yes, don't miss it, alright? Okay!
Yes, that's the announcement. So, so, so, so. Wah, sugoi ne! Wah.
Yes, that's the announcement. So, so, so, so. Wow, amazing! Wow.
Enggak keras, Ogees? Ah, enggak mau, enggak mau. Pulang! Mau putar pamer ekor dulu lah. This is my tail.
Not loud enough, Ogees? Ah, I don't want to, I don't want to. Go home! Let me show off my tail first. This is my tail.
So you can, uh, you can see it, uh, what is it? Uh, wiggling, uh, to your heart content. Thank you so much. Oh my god, this stream is all about about tails.
So you can, uh, you can see it, uh, what is it? Uh, wiggling, uh, to your heart's content. Thank you so much. Oh my god, this stream is all about tails.
So guys, I'm sorry, you need, you need to say farewell to the tail right now.
Not actually the last, but, uh, today sebelum lagu terakhir itu, ah, ada yang ingin Risu sampaikan, gitu.
Not actually the last, but, uh, before the last song earlier, uh, there's something Risu wanted to convey, like that.
The time I set myself here
I've decided to do my best
All the stories, Moments, and memories we shared are what's precious to me
The supports I've received are what keeps me going and made me who I am today
The support I've received is what keeps me going and made me who I am today
I can only convey my feelings through limited words, but this feeling of gratitude is real...
Thanks for being with me throughout my journey
This is a beginning of a new chapter
This is the beginning of a new chapter
in a path that is forged by wishes, hardworking, and lots of support for you, Risunes,
in a path that is forged by wishes, hard work, and lots of support for you, Risunes,
I've made this song
Let the time
send this song
to more people
as we wished for it
Sing it out together
Our hopes...
Our dream...
Surely...
it will reach the sky.
are my eyes deceiving me ? your soul starts to fade
Are my eyes deceiving me? Your soul starts to fade.
unleash your magic to me
now it 's time not to worry do believe in me
Now it's time not to worry, do believe in me.
a journey we have to see
rurira rari ra incomplete melody
sung with a sweet but yet a sad symphony
Sung with a sweet yet sad symphony.
unwavering spirit that you told me
how can i do it when you 're not even here
How can I do it when you're not even here?
oh , let me let out the words i could say to you right now ,
Oh, let me let out the words I could say to you right now,
i can only tell you a bit
overwhelm me with your kindness is a gift that i could never ever trade with anything
Overwhelm me with your kindness; it's a gift that I could never ever trade with anything.
let the time send this song to your ears
i hope one day you will sing it to me
versatile melody that i tried to write
every day i would pray in my heart , cause i 'm reaching the sky
Every day I would pray in my heart, 'cause I'm reaching the sky.
in a time full of worries no light i could see
do you want me to be here ?
Do you want me to be here?
nulling all the emotions you 're supposed to feel
Nulling all the emotions you're supposed to feel.
even voice i wanna hear
shalala shalila incomplete melody
arriving in your ears like it 's destiny
Arriving in your ears like it's destiny.
rurira rari ra incomplete memory
showing all the warmth that i have ever feel
Showing all the warmth that I have ever felt.
呼んで
Call out,
sing out
夜の記憶
Memories of the night,
shout out
火は燃える
The fire burns.
星屑の欠片たちは今願いになる 新たな喜びを願うの定
Stardust fragments now become wishes, praying for new joy.
rurira rari ra
a complete melody
has been sung in the world so far you can't see let the wind , let the sea carry this melody
Has been sung in a world so far you can't see. Let the wind, let the sea carry this melody.
legacy , timeless song that carry all the wish i believe
Legacy, a timeless song that carries all the wishes. I believe.
all the words i could say right now , i can only tell you a little bit
All the words I could say right now, I can only tell you a little bit.
overwhelm me with your kindness is a gift that
Overwhelm me with your kindness; it's a gift that
i could never ever trade with anything
let the time send this song to you
i hope one day you will sing it to me
versatile melody that i tried to write
every day i will sing it aloud , and i will try to shine
Every day I will sing it aloud, and I will try to shine.
この声を聴いて
Listen to this voice,
terima kasih untuk semua perhatian yang telah kuterima
Thank you for all the attention I have received.
as gentle breeze passed through your soul this time i believe everything will be fine
As a gentle breeze passes through your soul this time, I believe everything will be fine.
terima kasih untuk semua perhatian yang telah kuterima
Thank you for all the attention I've received,
as gentle breeze passed through your soul this time
as a gentle breeze passed through your soul this time.
i believe, everything will be fine
every day i would sing it aloud, this is my time to shine
every day i will sing it aloud, and i will try to shine
Thank you for watching my 3D debut! I hope you enjoyed the show.
Without you, there will be no Ayunda Risu.
Let's do more fun things from now on as well!, GanbaRisu!
Ayunda Risu
- Ayunda Risu
3D Showcase #AyundaRisu3D